CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL BACKGROUND



Zulkarnain Muhammad
Marketing Communication Manager at Sabiya Marcomm

DoB: Jakarta, 30th August 1985

Adress: Jl. Teratai Putih No. 28 Rengas, Ciputat Timur, Tangsel

Mobile Phone: 081318584160 / 087882227550

Email: joule.muhammad@gmail.com

SUMMARY

As a Bachelor degree in Business and Management majoring marketing, Zulkarnain started his career as a creative specialist over couple years ago. Yet, as his marketing background supplemented with sufficient knowledge in integrated marketing communication process area, which were gained through his experience in all areas of marketing including; PR, advertising, sales, fundraising, promotion, creative production, both on a strategizing and applications basis and also Magister Management post-graduate Program, Zulkarnain shaped up to become well-rounded professional over period of time.

These unique combination factors between Marketing and Business along with current valuable experience in Marketing Communication related area, provide Zulkarnain with creative capability to gain success in any area of business in the future ahead.

EXPERIENCES

Marketing Communication Manager Sabiya Marcomm

January 2014 – Present

Promotion and Media Support Services Consultants who handles; Integrated Marketing Communication Strategies, Advertising and Media Placement, Corporate Branding, Product Campaign (ATL, BTL, TTL), Graphic Boutique, Multimedia, etc

In this current role, Zulkarnain led a team to conduct creative idea, strategies, and all areas on integrated marketing communication which might involved internal and/ or external parties such as, Sabiya Marcomm employee and third party vendor. Zulkarnain also responsible to manage all creative idea for the purpose of promotion and media support services as a support based on the clients expectation and also giving trust to all clients. Beside main role above, Zulkarnain also responsible to help the organization in develops a marketing strategy that effectively markets the organization and makes decisions relative to the selection, promotion, utilization, retention and compensation of Marketing and Communications staff. Amongst clients handled were: Darul Qur'an PPPA, Dompet Dhuafa, Hutama Karya Realtindo, Delphys, Bank BNI, Blu-jek Indonesia, BCI Asia Indonesia, Shell Indonesia, Mountoya, Bazma Pertamina, Toyota, Telkomsel, Indofood, CIMB Niaga, GCC Indonesia, Toyota, Memory Group, Nestle, Ace Hardware, Informa, etc

Marketing Communication Manager Ultimate Learning Institute (ULi)

March 2013 - Des 2013

An Australian company which runs on providing industry-focused education and training programs through contemporary program content and state-of-the-at methods of delivery.

As a Project Manager in Marketing Communication Department, Zulkarnain has responsibility to ensure that Integrated Marketing Communication in ULi is adequately managed. This responsibility includes Brand Activation, Sales Collateral and Support, Product Positioning and Branding, Web and Print Content Development, Marketing Strategies and Campaigns, Market Research, and also Public and Media Relations. Followings are details of responsibility undertaken:

- 1. Brand positioning of ULi in the market: come up with strategy and approtiate ULi marketing collaterals
- 2. Lead generation / costumer acquisition activities to assist sales to get new potential leads
- 3. Develop campaign plan, strategy, budget with measurable targets
- 4. Execute the campaign, with the assistance of the related ULi staff/division (if applicable)
- 5. Builds benefecial relationships with targeted press, radio & TV journalists, editors, and conference organizers
- 6. Create, manage, arrange, empowerment program conducted by ULi that involve many Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) in Indonesia as it partners
- 7. To develop, execute and monitor marketing survey to measure costumer satisfaction level of our services, relationship, and other related parameters
- 8. Conduct research on products sold
- 9. Create and maintenance ULi Sosial Media (Web, Blog, Facebook, Twitter, etc) / www.ulinstitute.com

Marketing Communication Manager Yayasan Dompet Dhuafa

March 2010 - March 2013 (3 years)

Non-profit organization in Indonesia aimed to enhance social status of the low-lived people by managing ZISWAF (Zakat, Infaq, Shadakah, Wakaf and other halal & legal funds) from individual, groups, corporations, and organizations.

Marketing Communication Manager

Zulkarnain's last position in Dompet Dhuafa was as a Marketing Communication Manager. With his role, Zulkarnain led a team to conduct integrated marketing communication on Dompet Dhuafa's ZISWAF program as a support to fundraising department. Manage corporate marketing and communications functions, overseeing a Rp 5 Bilion budget 10-member team. Doing direct brand management, PR, media relations, corporate positioning, product launches, advertising, fundraising collateral and tradeshow marketing. Following are details selected accomplishments:

- 1. Centralized communications
- 2. Developed and launched integrated, multi-channel print, catalog, web, and direct marketing campaigns that propelled fundraising from Rp 80 Billion (2010) to a projected Rp 120 Billion (2011), Rp 170 Billion (2012), and Rp 186 Billion (2013) yearend
- Created Web portal to transform previously archaic intranet into a dynamic website improving communication flow and adding an effective fundraising tool for fields reps (www.dompetdhafa.org, www.rumahsehatterpadu.or.id, www.zakat.or.id, www.tabungwakaf.com)

- 4. Wrote catalogs, course guides and training brochures that enchanced the fundraising reps' understanding of complex program features and helped them sell more effectively
- 5. Performed ongoing customer/market research and demographic profiling to identify and capitalize on unmet market needs ahead of the curve
- 6. Produced media kit that demonstrated key marketing analytics and demographics for use in fundraising presentations.
- 7. Leveraged strenghs in cost-effective marketing management and vendor negotiations to end each year an average of 15% underbudget (without compromising business growth goals)
- 8. Develop and manage overall Dompet Dhuafa's CSR (Corporate Social Responsibility) programs
- 9. Create and prepare production for Television Campaign Program: 'Datang Dari Hati' including location survey, script writing, shooting, create rundown events, and voice offer (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v7fUsToMBQ4)
- 10. Create, Manage, arrange, and supervise overall community radio programs (Radio Komunitas Swara Cinta Dompet Dhuafa)
- 11. Create, Manage, arrange, and supervise overall Zakat TV programs (www.zakat.tv)
- 12. Create, Manage, arrange, and supervise overall Disaster Radio Dompet Dhuafa (www.dompetdhuafa.org/radio)

Fundraising Area Manager – Lembaga Amil Zakat Dompet Dhuafa (LAZ DD):

In his careers at Dompet Dhuafa, Zulkarnain led a team which might involved internal and/ or external parties such as, Dompet Dhuafa employee and volunteer/outsource to conduct Zakat program in Jabodetabek area. He responsible to perform on following matters:

- 1. Develop marketing plan and event for Zakat fundraising in Jabodetabek areas
- 2. Develop and manage 'Zakat Penghasilan' from various companies (Citibank, Indosat, Telkomsel, Indofood, etc.)
- 3. Liaise and coordinate with media for promoting marketing program through printed media, television, and radio
- 4. Manage Zakat booth in Jabodetabek areas to accomplish target (Rp 7 Billion/month for the entire areas)
- 5. wrote catalogs, course guides and training brochures that enchanced the volunteer reps' understanding of complex program features and helped them sell more effectively

Fundraising Executive – Wagf Rumah Sehat Terpadu (RST):

In his early careers at Dompet Dhuafa, Zulkarnain acted as fundraising for Waqf program Rumah Sehat Terpadu (free hospital for dhuafa). As an internal support staff, he responsible to led market launch of new programs Rumah Sehat Terpadu (free hospital for dhuafa). Collecting waqf from personal and corporate, collaborated with Department of Health, Department of CSR, and created campaigns and implementation of sales activity for generating Rp 65 Bilion in annual fundraising.

Creative (Broadcast Development Program) Global TV

February 2009 – February 2010

Private television station.

Broadcast Development Program in Global TV similar with Management Trainee in other companies. As a Creative in Production Unit, Zulkarnain has responsibility to ensure that Creative program in Global TV is adequately managed. This responsibility includes develop program proposal, budgeting, talent casting, script writing, voice offer, rundown event, and shooting for several new television programs: 'Deni Manusia Ikan', 'Tamu Gokil', and

'Handmade'. And also coordinate with support talent of new program and participate become a creative team for MTV Staying Alive 2010.

Content Development Executive Axcomm Infotec Centero

January 2008 - January 2009

Content provider, VAS, and IT Solution.

After graduated from Universitas Widyatama and completed apprentice program at several companies, Zulkarnain started his career as an Content Development Specialist at PT. Axcomm infotece Centero. As part of support team, his main duty is to provide daily contents for several programs and maintain daily social networks.

OTHER EXPERIENCES AND ACTIVITIES

Guest Lecture

Universitas Muhammadiyah Jakarta, Universitas Pamulang, Bina Sarana Informatika, Universitas Umar Usman

2012 – Present

Speaker

for Economy Creative, Philanthropy, Humanitarian relief and disaster, Community Empowerment, Community Radio events

2011 - Present

FORMAL EDUCATION

Universitas Muhammadiyah Jakarta Magister Management majoring Management Education and Training Institution 2014

Universitas Widyatama Bachelor of Business and Management majoring Marketing Management 2007

MEMBERSHIP OF PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

Jaringan Radio Komunitas Indonesia (JRKI)

2012 - 2013

Association of Fundraising Professionals (Indonesia Chapter)

2010 - 2013

Asosiasi Konsultan Komunikasi Pemasaran (MCCA)

2012 - Present

CERTIFICATION

Judge on Business Plan Competition Certification Temu Ilmiah Regional Jabodetabek (FoSSEI dan Universitas Muhammadiyah Jakarta) February 2015 Speaker on Business Plan Competition Certification Temu Ilmiah Regional Jabodetabek (FoSSEI dan Universitas Muhammadiyah Jakarta) February 2015

Certificate of Participation
Seminar Marketing and Promotion Media Branding for FMCG Industry (Singapore Management University)
March 2013

SKILLS

- Marketing Strategies and Campaigns
- Corporate Social Responsibility
- Corporate Communications
- Creative Team Leadership
- Product Positioning & Branding
- Web & Print Content Development
- Focus Group & Market Research
- Development of Training Materials
- Sales Collateral & Support
- Public & Media Relations
- New Product Launch